Thomas Chestnut

Glenolden, PA • (267) 324-9101

Email: thomaschestnut00@gmail.com • **LinkedIn**: linkedin.com/in/thomas-chestnut

Portfolio: tchestnut85.github.io • GitHub: github.com/tchestnut85

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Full Stack Web Developer experienced in front-end and back-end development utilizing methods such as Agile development, RESTful APIs and MVC structure. Skilled in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, and Express.js among other tools and frameworks.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS

Other: Node.js, Express.js, OOP, RESTful APIs, AJAX, Git, Agile Development, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, ORM, MVC, Handlebars, TDD, Jest, Webpack, PWA, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania LPS Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development (Expected February 2021)

July 2020 - February 2021

Temple University, Philadelphia PA - Bachelor's Degree

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Studies

August 2003 - May 2008

EXPERIENCE

Spark Therapeutics — EHS Associate

Philadelphia, PA

June 2019 - Present

- Managed hazardous waste programs at multiple sites and associated recordkeeping and reporting.
- Collaborated with EHS team members to ensure laboratory safety processes and procedures are adhered to.
- Communicated with laboratory staff regarding safety or compliance issues and resolutions.
- Inspected laboratory area for safety and waste management compliance.

Triumvirate Environmental at GlaxoSmithKline — Assistant Program Manager

King of Prussia/Collegeville, PA

May 2017 - June 2019

- Managed team members and hazardous waste programs at multiple sites.
- Performed safety inspections as well as various regulatory environmental monitoring and sampling.
- Trained team members on various job functions.

Triumvirate Environmental at GlaxoSmithKline — Senior Environmental Specialist

King of Prussia/Collegeville, PA

January 2016 - May 2017

- Packaged laboratory chemical waste to meet regulatory requirements for shipment and disposal.
- Scheduled and performed waste shipments in conjunction with transportation vendors.